[
{
"id":"1",
"question":"Learn from yesterday, live for today, hope for tomorrow. The important thing is not to stop ____________.’ Fill in the blank to complete this quotation by Albert Einstein.",
"A": "Wishing",
"B": "Questioning",
"C": "Thinking",
"answer": "Questioning"
},
{
"id":"2",
"question":"The name of which spice comes from the French word for ‘nail’?",
"A": "Cinnamon",
"B": "Cardamom",
"C": "Clove",
"answer": "Clove" 
},
{
"id":"3",
"question":"In India, the train Lifeline Express is a…",
"A": "Hospital",
"B": "Bank",
"C": "Primary School",
"answer": "Hospital"
},
{
"id":"4",
"question":"Which Asian mountain is also known as the Savage Mountain due to the extreme difficulty of ascent?",
"A": "Kanchenjunga",
"B": "K2",
"C": "Lhotse",
"answer": "K2"
},
{
"id":"5",
"question":"In 1964, which portfolio was given to Indira Gandhi in the government of Lal Bahadur Shastri?",
"A": " Defence ",
"B": "Home",
"C": "Information and Broadcasting",
"answer": "Information and Broadcasting"
},
{
"id":"6",
"question":"In Alice’s Adventures in Wonderland, which game was played by the Queen of Hearts using hedgehogs as balls?",
"A": "Quintet",
"B": "Quidditch",
"C": "Croquet",
"answer": "Croquet"
},
{
"id":"7",
"question":"With which unfortunate incident would you associate the warplane Enola Gay?",
"A": "Sinking of the ship Bismark",
"B": "The Hiroshima bombing",
"C": "Storming of Bastille",
"answer": "The Hiroshima bombing"
},
{
"id":"8",
"question":"Odhra Magadha is the precursor to which Indian dance form?",
"A": "Kuchipudi",
"B": "Kathak",
"C": " Odissi",
"answer": "Odissi"
},
{
"id":"9",
"question":"Who composed music for the 1969 film Goopy Gyne Bagha Byne?",
"A": "Satyajit Ray",
"B": "Ravi Shankar",
"C": "Shiv-Hari",
"answer": "Satyajit Ray"
},
{
"id":"10",
"question":"Where in the human body is the stapedius muscle situated?",
"A": "Nose",
"B": "Ears",
"C": "Leg",
"answer": "Ears"
},
{
"id":"11",
"question":"Apart from Venus, which planet rotates from east to west?",
"A": "Jupiter",
"B": "Mars",
"C": "Uranus",
"answer": "Uranus"
},
{
"id":"12",
"question":"Which country was Herodotus referring to when he said: ‘There is no country that possesses so many wonders, nor any, that such a number of works that defy description’?",
"A": "China",
"B": "Germany",
"C": "Egypt",
"answer": "Egypt"
},
{
"id":"13",
"question":"Which famous world leader was accused at the Rivonia Trial?",
"A": "Martin Luther King",
"B": "Subhas Chandra Bose",
"C": "Nelson Mandela",
"answer": "Nelson Mandela"
},
{
"id":"14",
"question":"In Hindu mythology, who has a mansion named Vaijayanta and a sword named Paranjaya?",
"A": " Vishnu",
"B": "Shiva",
"C": "Indra",
"answer": "Indra"
},
{
"id":"15",
"question":"What is parasol a kind of?",
"A": "Umbrella",
"B": "Footwear",
"C": "Bracelet",
"answer": "Umbrella"
},
{
"id":"16",
"question":"What was the pen name of William Sydney Porter?",
"A": "Mark Twain",
"B": "Oscar Wilde",
"C": "O’ Henry",
"answer": "O’ Henry"
},
{
"id":"17",
"question":"Which spice consists of the seed of the Myristica fragrans, a tropical evergreen tree?",
"A": " Cardamom",
"B": "Clove",
"C": "Nutmeg",
"answer": "Nutmeg"
},
{
"id":"18",
"question":"Which leader wrote the Srimad Bhagavad Gita Rahasya while he was jailed in Myanmar?",
"A": " Bal Gangadhar Tilak",
"B": "Motilal Nehru",
"C": "Gopal Krishna Gokhale",
"answer": "Bal Gangadhar Tilak"
},
{
"id":"19",
"question":"Who was born in Gwalior in 1945 to Haafiz Ali Khan?",
"A": "Amjad Ali Khan",
"B": "Bismillah Khan",
"C": "Ali Akbar Khan",
"answer": "Amjad Ali Khan"
},
{
"id":"20",
"question":"Which is the largest internal organ in the human body?",
"A": "Liver",
"B": "Heart",
"C": "Lung",
"answer": "Liver"
},
{
"id":"21",
"question":"After whom is the chemical element with atomic number 102 named?",
"A": "Albert Einstein",
"B": "Alfred Bernhard Nobel",
"C": "Isaac Newton",
"answer": "Alfred Bernhard Nobel"
},
{
"id":"22",
"question":"In the Mahabharata, who was granted a divine inward eye so that he could see and relate the events of the battlefield to Dhritarashtra?",
"A": "Sanjaya",
"B": "Purochana",
"C": "Shikhandi",
"answer": "Sanjaya"
},
{
"id":"23",
"question":"The capital of which Scandinavian country is located on the islands of Zealand and Amager?",
"A": " Norway",
"B": "Sweden",
"C": "Denmark",
"answer": "Denmark"
},
{
"id":"24",
"question":"Complete this Sunderlal Bahuguna phrase which he coined during the Chipko Movement: ‘Ecology is permanent _____.’",
"A": "Economy",
"B": "Sociology",
"C": "Biology",
"answer": "Economy"
},
{
"id":"25",
"question":"By what name is K’ung Fu-tzu better known to the Western world?",
"A": "Confucius",
"B": "Lao Tzu",
"C": "Fa-Hien",
"answer": "Confucius"
},
{
"id":"26",
"question":"Which spice was introduced to India around 1800 CE by the East India Company in its spice garden in Courtallam, Tamil Nadu?",
"A": "Clove",
"B": "Pepper",
"C": "Cardamom",
"answer": "Clove"
},
{
"id":"27",
"question":"In Twenty Thousand Leagues Under the Sea, what was the name of the warship in which Captain Nemo sailed?",
"A": "Basillus",
"B": "Nautilus",
"C": "Remolus",
"answer": "Nautilus"
},
{
"id":"28",
"question":"Bidriware derives its name from the town of Bidar. In which state is Bidar located?",
"A": "Karnataka",
"B": "Kerala",
"C": "Gujarat",
"answer": "Karnataka"
},
{
"id":"29",
"question":"In India, who heads the Department of Space?",
"A": "The president",
"B": "The prime minister",
"C": "The defence minister",
"answer": "The prime minister"
},
{
"id":"30",
"question":"Which actor won the National Award in the Best Actor category for Dastak in 1971 and Koshish in 1973?",
"A": "Dev Anand",
"B": "Sanjeev Kumar",
"C": "Dilip Kumar",
"answer": "Sanjeev Kumar"
},
{
"id":"31",
"question":"Adams, Leverrier, Galle and Lassell are some of the rings of which planet?",
"A": "Neptune",
"B": "Saturn",
"C": "Jupiter",
"answer": "Neptune"
},
{
"id":"32",
"question":"In the Mahabharata, who among these was killed by Krishna?",
"A": "Karna",
"B": "Ekalavya",
"C": "Jayadratha",
"answer": "Ekalavya"
},
{
"id":"33",
"question":"Which famous philosopher was also the tutor of Alexander the Great?",
"A": "Aristotle",
"B": "Socrates",
"C": "Rousseau",
"answer": "Aristotle"
},
{
"id":"34",
"question":"What was defined as ‘three grains of barley, dry and round, placed end to end lengthwise’?",
"A": "Centimetre",
"B": "Millimetre",
"C": "Inch",
"answer": "Inch"
},
{
"id":"35",
"question":"The name of which of these means the ‘gilded one’ in Spanish?",
"A": "El Dorado",
"B": "Buenos Aires",
"C": "El Nino",
"answer": "El Dorado"
},
{
"id":"36",
"question":"Which 1852 book was smuggled into Russia in Yiddish to evade the czarist censor?",
"A": "Uncle Tom’s Cabin",
"B": "Alice in Wonderland",
"C": "Das Kapital",
"answer": "Uncle Tom’s Cabin"
},
{
"id":"37",
"question":"Who was the prime minister of the United Kingdom at the time of Queen Elizabeth II’s coronation?",
"A": "Neville Chamberlain",
"B": "Winston Churchill",
"C": "Harold McMillan",
"answer": "Winston Churchill"
},
{
"id":"38",
"question":"Tomato, sweet corn, oxtail, bird’s nest, chimney and French onion are all …",
"A": "Types of soup",
"B": "Breeds of cats",
"C": "Sporting events",
"answer": "Types of soup"
},
{
"id":"39",
"question":"Which work is often referred to as the fifth veda?",
"A": "Panchtantra",
"B": "Natyashastra",
"C": "Arthshastra",
"answer": "Natyashastra"
},
{
"id":"40",
"question":"Which Indi-pop singer was born Sujata, and was known for her hit ‘Made in India’?",
"A": "Sunita Rao",
"B": "Alisha Chinai",
"C": "Pravati Khan",
"answer": "Alisha Chinai"
},
{
"id":"41",
"question":"Which of these elements is not named after a scientist?",
"A": "Einsteinium",
"B": "Ruthenium",
"C": "Curium",
"answer": "Ruthenium"
},
{
"id":"42",
"question":"In which present-day country was the Battle of Waterloo fought?",
"A": "France",
"B": "Iran",
"C": "Belgium",
"answer": "Belgium"
},
{
"id":"43",
"question":"Which rakshasa took the form of a golden deer to lure Lakshmana away, leaving Sita unprotected?",
"A": "Tadaka",
"B": "Mareecha",
"C": "Nikumbha",
"answer": "Mareecha"
},
{
"id":"44",
"question":"In India, ‘Duty Unto Death’ is the motto of which organization?",
"A": "Border Security Force",
"B": "National Cadet Corps",
"C": "Central Bureau of Investigation",
"answer": "Border Security Force"
},
{
"id":"45",
"question":"Which country’s highest peak is Mount Ararat?",
"A": "China",
"B": "Turkey",
"C": "Iran",
"answer": "Turkey"
},
{
"id":"46",
"question":"What do you call a system of serving when a meal, consisting of several dishes is set out and guests serve themselves?",
"A": "Buffet",
"B": " A la carte",
"C": "Menu",
"answer": "Buffet"
},
{
"id":"47",
"question":"With which artist would you associate The Thinker, a statue cast in bronze?",
"A": "Auguste Rodin",
"B": "Michelangelo",
"C": "Leonardo da Vinci",
"answer": "Auguste Rodin"
},
{
"id":"48",
"question":"Kisan Ghat in Delhi is the memorial ground of which famous leader?",
"A": "Charan Singh",
"B": "Rajiv Gandhi",
"C": "Jagjivan Ram",
"answer": "Charan Singh"
},
{
"id":"49",
"question":"Edward Lear was famous for his five-line humorous poems. What is the correct term for this style of poetry?",
"A": "Elegy",
"B": "Sonnet",
"C": "Limerick",
"answer": "Limerick"
},
{
"id":"50",
"question":"Which character did actor Leonard Nimoy portray in Star Trek V: The Final Frontier?",
"A": "Spock",
"B": "Kirk",
"C": "McCoy",
"answer": "Spock"
}
]